♪♪
- Sweet silence of a quad-less house.
没有四轮车的宁静真好。
- [sighs] I love it when the kids spend
叹气 我喜欢孩子们去你妈妈家过周末。
the weekend at your mother's.
哦，我希望周末能更长一些。
- Oh, I wish it was a longer weekend.
哦。
- Oh.
嗯，喂？
- Uh, hello?
你知道我们站在这儿，对吧？
- You know we're standing here, right?
[深吸一口气][呼气]
both: [inhale deeply] [exhale]
孩子们，欢迎回家。
- Hey, kids! Welcome home.
我们好想你们。这种周末太长了。
- We missed you so much. These weekends are way too long.
我们非常想念你。这些周末太长了。
- Whoo-hoo! Oh, Tommy, Tommy,
哇哦！哦，汤米，汤米，
my little salami. Get over here
我的小萨拉米。快过来
and hug your mommy.
拥抱你的妈妈。
- Uh-huh. I hate it when you call me
嗯哼。我不喜欢你叫我
your little salami.
你的小萨拉米。
I'm a big salami now.
我现在是个大萨拉米了。
- Anybody else never want to eat salami again?
还有人再也不想吃萨拉米了吗？
- Thanks for letting me sleep over.
谢谢你让我留宿。
You know I'm--I'm not the best driver in the dark.
你知道我在黑暗中——我不是最好的司机。
But in the day, people are always honking and waving at me.
但在白天，人们总是对我按喇叭和挥手。
- Oh, yeah, they're waving, Grammy.
- 哦，是的，他们在挥手，奶奶。
- Well, if you'll excuse me, I have to go make
- 那么，如果你们不介意的话，我得去
a deposit in my local branch.
我的当地分行存点钱。
- He has to make a doody.
- 他得去上厕所。
- He never goes at Grammy's. The porcelain figurines
- 他从不在奶奶家上厕所。她浴室里的瓷像
in her bathroom freak him out.
让他感到不安。
- Especially when we whisper through the vent
- 特别是当我们通过通风口低声说话
to make him think that they're talking.
让他以为它们在交谈时。
- We see you.
- 我们看见你了。
- Other than tormenting their brother, did the kids behave?
除了捉弄他们的弟弟，孩子们表现得好吗？
- Of course they did. They're Grammy's little angels.
当然好。他们是奶奶的小天使。
- We're always on our best behavior
我们在奶奶家总是表现得很乖。
when we're at Grammy's house.
那只是因为如果你表现好，
- That's only because if you behave,
她会奖励你一些很酷的礼物。
she rewards you with some really cool gift.
什么？
- What? - That's not true.
那不是真的。
- Frankly, I'm insulted. - Yeah.
老实说，我感到被冒犯了。
- So did we get our good-behavior gift yet?
是啊。
- Well, I was gonna unpack first.
那我们得到好行为礼物了吗？
all: Ugh.
- But I guess I could give it to you now.
all: Yay!
- No, you know what, Mom? They can wait.
all: Ugh.
- Seriously, why do we even bother behaving?
- Do you even hear yourselves? You shouldn't have to be
rewarded for good behavior. Good behavior is its own reward.
- And it is, Father. But is this really fair
to Grandmother, whose one joy is seeing the smiles on her
little grandchildren's faces when we open
我们打开她精心准备的礼物时，
her thoughtful gift?
她看到我们这些小孙子的笑脸，这是她唯一的快乐。
- How could you do this to your own mother?
- 你怎么能这样对待你自己的母亲？
Shame on you, Tommy Salami.
- 汤米·萨拉米，你真可耻。
- Mommy, I'm sorry.
- 妈妈，对不起。
- Snap out of it, Salami, the kids are playing you.
- 振作点，萨拉米，孩子们在利用你。
You can open that gift tomorrow.
- 你可以明天再打开那个礼物。
- And only if we get some of that "Grandma's house" behavior
- 而且只有在我们自己家里表现出那种“奶奶家”的行为。
in our own house.
- 来吧，奶奶，你打算支持萨拉米的胡说八道吗？
- Come on, Grammy, are you going to support Salami's baloney?
- 不管你父母说什么，都得听。
- Whatever your parents say goes.
- 父母说什么就是什么。
Their house, their rules.
他们家，他们定规矩。
- You know what, what's one more day?
- 你知道吗，再多一天又何妨？
We can do this.
我们能做到的。
- But before we commit, a moment.
- 但在我们决定之前，稍等一下。
[whispering indistinctly]
[低语不清晰]
- We'd like to know what the gift is to see
- 我们想知道礼物是什么，以便看看
if behaving is worth our while.
表现得值不值得。
- Before we answer, a moment.
- 在我们回答之前，稍等一下。
No.
不行。
all: Ugh.
全体：呃。
- Come on, let's go hide this gift.
来吧，我们把这礼物藏起来。
- I can't behave for another day!
我再也装不下去了！
- I know, I've got misbehavior bursting out of me!
我知道，我快要忍不住了！
- All right, they're hiding the gift, so we have at least
好吧，他们正在藏礼物，所以我们至少有
30 seconds to let this bad behavior out.
30秒的时间来释放这种不良行为。
Ready, go!
准备好了，开始！
- So are you kids ready to behave?
那么，你们准备好表现好了吗？
- [exhales]
（呼气）
We're ready.
我们准备好了。
But Squishy might need another minute.
但是Squishy可能还需要一分钟。
[upbeat music]
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
[whistling]
♪ ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
[upbeat music]
- And there.
- 好了。
That should keep you calm and well-behaved.
那应该会让你保持冷静和守规矩。
- I haven't felt this safe since I was a baby.
- 我自从还是个婴儿以来，从未感到如此安全。
- Me too.
- 我也是。
- This is ridiculous.
- 这太荒谬了。
- I'm with Dawn. This is stupid.
- 我同意Dawn的看法。这太愚蠢了。
- Look, we can't stay in these swaddles all day.
- 看，我们不能整天裹在这些襁褓里。
- Only 'cause you wouldn't let Dooley diaper us.
- 只是因为你不会让Dooley给我们换尿布。
- That was never part of the deal.
- 那从来不是协议的一部分。
- Everybody just unswaddle.
- 大家就解开襁褓吧。
- Hey, Dooley, why do you keep looking out the window?
- 嘿，Dooley，你为什么一直往窗外看？
- I'm just keeping an eye on your neighbors' bikes.
我只是留意一下你们邻居的自行车。
They shouldn't leave them on the front porch like that.
他们不应该把自行车放在前门廊那里。
- Yeah, that's true. The police still haven't
是啊，确实。警察还没抓到那个偷车贼。
caught that bike thief. He got six more this week.
他这周又偷了六辆。
- Look at them, so exposed,
看看它们，那么暴露，
so unwatched, so unloved.
无人看管，无人爱护。
I gotta go.
我得走了。
- Ah, what a guy. Swaddling us,
啊，真是个好人。给我们裹着，
protecting the neighbors' bikes.
还保护邻居的自行车。
- That Dooley is a giver.
那个Dooley真是乐于助人。
- And he looks good in a hat.
而且他戴帽子很好看。
The average kid could not pull that off.
一般孩子可驾驭不了这顶帽子。
Nope. Nope.
不行。不行。
- Nope.
不行。
- Wait, somebody should probably go check to make sure
等等，应该有人去确认一下
the garage is locked.
车库门是不是锁好了。
Our bikes are out there.
我们的自行车还在外面呢。
- Forget the bikes. We've got frozen
别管自行车了，我们还有
burritos in there! Move.
冷冻墨西哥卷饼在里面呢！快走。
- Your Grandma sure does have odd taste in hats.
你奶奶对帽子的品味确实很独特。
- That's not what the Duke of Windsor said, Mae.
- 梅，那不是温莎公爵说的。
And he knows hats.
他可是懂帽子的。
- You know the Duke of Windsor, Grammy Harper?
- 哈珀奶奶，你认识温莎公爵？
- That's her dog.
- 那是她的狗。
- But he does know hats.
- 但他确实懂帽子。
- Now, you kids just keep behaving yourselves
- 现在，孩子们，你们就乖乖地待着
while Grammy watches her stories.
让奶奶看她的电视剧。
[laughs]
[笑]
That cute little fella
那个可爱的小家伙
lives in a pineapple.
住在菠萝里。
- Guys, you won't believe what I found in the garage.
- 伙计们，你们不会相信我在车库里发现了什么。
- Grandma's gift. - Better: chimichangas.
- 奶奶的礼物。 - 更确切地说：芝士炸饼。
- No, Grandma's gift. - Oh, yeah, I found that too.
- 不，是奶奶的礼物。 - 哦，对，我也找到了那个。
- Why did you bring it in here?
- 你为什么把它带到这里来？
- 'Cause I need to heat it up. - Not the chimichanga, the gift.
- 因为我需要加热它。 - 不是芝士炸饼，是礼物。
- That too. It was in the freezer
- 那个也是。它被冻在冰箱里
behind the chimichangas.
在芝士炸饼的后面。
- Ooh, don't open that. - You gotta vent it, dude.
- 哦，别打开那个。 - 你得先放气，伙计。
- Not the chimichanga! We're not supposed to
- 不是芝士炸饼！我们不应该
have that present until we behave.
在我们表现好之前拿到那个礼物。
- Well, Mom and Dad are out running errands.
- 嗯，爸爸妈妈出去办事了。
Now's our chance. - Yeah, don't you want
现在是我们动手的好机会。 - 对啊，你不想知道里面是什么吗？
to know what's in there?
- 我已经知道了。一点小chimichanga，一点小changa。
- I already know. A little chimi, a little changa.
- Dicky，我们永远不要谈论那个chimichanga！
- Dicky, we will never be talking about the chimichanga!
- 那就别问了。
- Then stop asking about it.
[微波炉发出哔哔声]
[microwave beeping]
- 我看这不会有什么好结果。 - 什么，我们打开礼物？
- I don't see this going well. - What, us opening the gift?
- 不，Dicky用微波炉加热chimichanga。
- No, Dicky microwaving the chimichanga.
四分钟高温？那东西会炸的。
Four minutes on high? That thing's gonna blow.
- 我要把它放回去。 - 哦，不，你不能。
- I'm gonna go put this back.
我打算把它放回去。
- Oh, no, you're not.
哦，不行。
- Come on, stay strong. What's one more day?
拜托，坚持一下。多等一天能怎样？
all: Ugh.
呃。
- Look, we're just gonna open it and see what's inside.
这样，我们打开看看里面是什么。
- We can't. - Why not?
不行。
What's the worst that could happen?
为什么不行？
- "What's the worst that could happen"?
最坏能怎么样？
"What's the worst that could happen"?
“最坏能怎么样？”
I'll tell you the worst that could happen.
Seriously? You're not even gonna
说真的？你连听我告诉你最坏的情况都不愿意？
listen to me tell you what's the worst that could happen?
听我说说最坏的情况都不愿意？
- You didn't listen to us when we told you
你当初没听我们的，叫你待在厨房里。
to stay in the kitchen.
放松点，我们只是小心翼翼地打开包装纸，看看它有多棒，
- Relax, we're just gonna delicately open
然后再小心翼翼地把它包回去。
the wrapping paper, see how awesome it is,
你们不能。
and then delicately close it back up.
谢谢你打开礼物，Ricky。
- You can't. [all gasp]
所有人：无人机！
- Thanks for opening the present, Ricky.
好了，现在我们知道是什么了，让我们找个办法重新包装它，然后……
- [gasp] all: A drone!
- Okay, well, now we know what it is, so let's just
好吧，既然现在我们知道这是什么了，那就让我们
find a way to rewrap it and...
想办法重新包装它然后...
put it back.
放回去。
- Or, you know, we could fly it around for a minute.
或者，你知道，我们可以让它飞一会儿。
- Or two. - Yeah, what could happen
或者两分钟。
in a minute? - Or two?
是啊，一分钟或两分钟能发生什么？
- You can't even cook a chimichanga in a minute or two.
你甚至不能在一两分钟内煮好一个芝士卷饼。
- Unless you're following the directions.
除非你按照说明书操作。
- Come on, guys. This is wrong.
拜托，伙计们。这样做不对。
Mae, back me up here.
梅，支持我一下。
- Oh, no, this genie's out of the bottle.
哦，不，这个精灵已经从瓶子里出来了。
I say we fly this sucker till the chimichanga blows.
我说我们飞这个家伙直到奇米昌加爆炸。
[drone whirring]
[无人机嗡嗡声]
all: Oooh.
哇。
Ahh.
啊。
- All right, you've ooh-ed, you've ahh-ed,
好了，你们已经哇过了，也啊过了，
now let's put it back in the box.
现在让我们把它放回盒子里。
- Careful, Ricky, the remote is sensitive.
小心，里基，遥控器很敏感。
- I got this. This "L" obviously means "land."
我明白了。这个“L”显然意味着“降落”。
[whirring] - [gasps]
[嗡嗡声] - [喘气声]
[crash]
- Or "left."
- 或者“左”。
- Well, it definitely left the garage.
- 好吧，它肯定离开了车库。
- And left a hole in the window.
- 还在窗户上留下了一个洞。
- And left our yard.
- 并且离开了我们的院子。
- Speaking of things that are out of here,
- 说到离开这里的东西，
I'm out of here.
我也要走了。
- Nice job, Ricky. And you were worried
- 干得好，Ricky。你还担心
just opening it was the worst that could happen.
只是打开它是最糟糕的事情。
- Ricky needs to be swaddled.
- Ricky需要被包裹起来。
♪ ♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
♪ ♪
- This is where the "Track My Drone" app
这就是“追踪我的无人机”应用
says it should be.
显示它应该在的地方。
- Hey, isn't this Dooley's house?
嘿，这不是杜利的家吗？
- Should we call him to see if he's home?
我们应该打电话给他看看他是否在家吗？
- Okay.
好的。
Dooley! Yo, Dooley!
杜利！哟，杜利！
Nope, not home.
不，不在家。
- We should probably go, then.
- 那我们可能该走了。
Here we go.
走吧。
Why aren't we going?
我们为什么不走？
- Because the drone's in there. - And we're out here.
- 因为无人机在里面。 - 而我们在外面。
- I get it, but breaking into Dooley's backyard
- 我明白，但闯入杜利的后院
is just going to get us into more trouble.
只会让我们陷入更多麻烦。
We should go home and come clean.
我们应该回家并坦白一切。
- We don't have to come clean.
- 我们不必坦白。
You're the one who did everything.
这一切都是你做的。
- Fine, I will accept responsibility
- 好吧，我会承担责任
for unwrapping the package.
对于拆开包裹。
- And losing the drone. - And losing the drone.
- 还有丢失了无人机。 - 还有丢失了无人机。
- And breaking the window. - And breaking the window.
- 还有打破了窗户。 - 还有打破了窗户。
- And breaking the wind. - And breaking the--
- 还有打破了风。 - 还有打破了--
hey, you can't pin that on me.
嘿，你不能把那事怪在我头上。
Fine, it was me. But I will not just
好吧，是我。但我不只是
stand idly by and allow you to commit the crime
袖手旁观，让你犯下闯入的罪行
of breaking and-- [grunts]
闯入和-- [咕哝]
Entering.
进入。
- Boy, you are just getting into all kinds of trouble today.
- 小子，你今天真是惹了一堆麻烦。
[gasps] There it is.
[倒抽一口气] 就在那儿。
- Oh.
- 哦。
- I am not a witness to this.
- 我与此事无关。
- Uh, guys, you might wanna come take a look at this.
- 呃，伙计们，你们可能想来看看这个。
- Whoa, that's a big tarp.
- 哇，那是一块大帆布。
- Not the tarp, the bikes.
- 不是帆布，是自行车。
- Whoa, six bikes. - I'm not looking at anything.
- 哇，六辆自行车。 - 我什么都没看。
[crashing]
[撞击声]
I just knocked over six bikes, didn't I?
我刚刚撞倒了六辆自行车，对吧？
- No, just five.
- 不，只有五辆。
[crash]
- Now it's six.
- 现在变成六辆了。
- Why does Dooley have all these bikes?
- 为什么杜利有这么多自行车？
- He loves bikes. You saw the way
- 他喜欢自行车。你看到他
he was lovingly eyeing those bikes across the street.
对面那些自行车时那爱不释眼的样子了。
- Yeah, he's a giver.
- 是啊，他是个给予者。
- Maybe he's not a giver. Maybe he's a taker.
- 也许他不是给予者。也许他是个索取者。
- What are you saying, Ricky?
- 你在说什么，瑞奇？
- I'm saying maybe Dooley...
- 我是说也许杜利...
is the bike thief.
是那个偷自行车的人。
- Oh, come on. You've seen the hat.
哦，得了吧。你见过那顶帽子。
That is not the hat of a bike thief.
那可不是偷自行车的人戴的帽子。
- It's also not the hat of a kid who rides
那也不是骑公主躲猫猫自行车的孩子戴的帽子。
a Princess Peek-A-Boo bike.
显然是他姐姐的。
- It's obviously his sister's.
看见了吗？车牌上写着'凯蒂'。
See? The license plate says "Katie."
他姐姐的名字叫朱莉。
- His sister's name is Julie.
他姐姐的名字叫朱莉·杜利？
- His sister's name is Julie Dooley?
不，杜利是他的名字。- 我以为那是他的姓。- 我们甚至不知道他叫什么名字。
- No, Dooley is his first name. - I thought it was his last name. - We don't even know his name.
我们当然知道。他就叫杜利·杜利。
- Sure we do. It's Dooley Dooley.
不，他是杜利·偷自行车的。
- No, it's Dooley Bike Thief.
不，是杜利偷车贼。
- Aha! So Dooley is his first name.
啊哈！所以杜利是他的名字。
- And maybe he's not just a bike thief.
而且也许他不仅仅是个偷车贼。
Maybe he's an everything thief.
也许他是个什么都偷的贼。
- I mean, it would explain how he gets whatever he wants
我是说，这可以解释他是怎么得到他想要的东西的
whenever he wants it.
无论何时他想要。
- Yeah, and every time we ask him where he gets
是的，每次我们问他从哪儿得到
his stuff, he just says, "I got a guy."
他的东西，他只是说，“我有个哥们。”
- He doesn't "got a guy," he is the guy.
他不是“有个哥们”，他自己就是那个人。
- How can a guy who looks so good in a hat
一个戴帽子看起来那么好的人
be so bad in a hat?
戴帽子怎么就这么糟糕？
- We have to call the cops.
- 我们得报警。
- No, then you'll have to admit that you
- 不行，那样你就得承认你闯进了后院。
broke into the backyard.
- 这会导致你承认你弄丢了无人机、打碎了窗户还拆了礼物。
- Which will lead you to admitting that you lost
- 你简直就是个怪物，伙计。
the drone and broke the window and opened the present.
- 你说得对。我们不能报警，
- You're kind of a monster, dude.
- 但我们也不能就这么让Dooley逍遥法外。
- You're right. We can't call the cops,
- 所以我们打算这么做。为了不让任何人惹上麻烦，
but we can't just let Dooley get away with this.
- 我们把这些自行车搬到我们的车库里，
- So here's what we're gonna do. To keep everybody
- 直到我们能把它们还回去。
out of trouble, we're gonna take these bikes
为了让大家都不惹上麻烦，我们打算把这些自行车
and keep them in our garage until we can return them
先放在我们的车库里，直到能归还给它们真正的主人。
to their rightful owners. - Sounds like a plan.
听起来是个计划。
- All right, let's do it. - All right.
好吧，就这么办。
- You know, it's going to feel really good to return
你知道吗，把这辆自行车还回去，看到小凯蒂的笑脸，
this bike and put a smile on little Katie's face.
感觉一定会很好。
[clanking]
咣当声
I am a monster.
我真是个怪物。
[bell pings]
铃声响起
♪ ♪
- There, good as new. Mom and Dad will never suspect.
好了，焕然一新。爸爸妈妈绝对不会怀疑。
- Neither will Katie.
凯蒂也不会。
- Hey, is this Katie's kickstand?
嘿，这是凯蒂的撑脚架吗？
- Let me see.
让我看看。
[crashing]
（撞击声）
- I'm gonna go with yes.
我猜是的。
- Well, at least you didn't ruin Grandma's present.
好吧，至少你没毁了奶奶的礼物。
- Oh, that was close.
哦，好险。
[smash]
（破碎声）
Uh, hey, uh, probably still good.
呃，嘿，可能还是好的。
[whirring]
[呼呼声]
[thud]
[砰的一声]
Yep, still good.
是的，还是好的。
♪ ♪
- Okay, the present is rewrapped and back in the freezer.
好了，礼物重新包装好并放回冰箱了。
The battery's been removed, we blame the broken window
电池已经取出来了，我们把窗户破损归咎于一只鸟，
on a bird, the bikes are fixed, now all we have to do
自行车也修好了，现在我们只需要找到车主。
is find the owners.
我们该怎么办关于杜利的事？
- What are we gonna do about Dooley?
别管杜利了。他是个无赖小偷。
- Forget about Dooley. He's a no-good thief.
不，我是说，他就在外面。
- No, I mean, he's right outside.
- 不，我是说，他就在外面。
- Do you think he sees us?
- 你觉得他看到我们了吗？
- That's how windows work.
- 窗户就是这样的。
- You think he knows we took his stolen bikes?
- 你认为他知道我们拿了那辆被偷的自行车吗？
- Why else would he be here?
- 不然他来这里干嘛？
- Man, he looks good in that hat.
- 伙计，他戴那顶帽子看起来真不错。
- Guys.
- 大家。
- Okay, everybody relax. Let's just open the door
- 好吧，大家都放松。我们开门看看他想要什么。嘿，杜利！
and see what he wants. Hey, Dooley!
- 没时间闲聊了。我有大麻烦了。
- No time for small talk. I am in huge trouble.
- 别担心，你还年轻。还有时间改变你的方式。
- Don't worry, you're still young.
别担心，你还年轻。
There's still time to change your ways.
还有时间改变你的生活方式。
- What? No, I must've left my back gate open,
什么？不，我一定是忘了关后门，
and the bike thief stole my dad's bike collection.
然后那个偷车贼偷了我爸爸的自行车收藏。
But what do you mean by "change my ways"?
但你说的“改变我的方式”是什么意思？
- What do you mean "your dad's bike collection"?
你说的“你爸爸的自行车收藏”是什么意思？
- My dad's a bike collector.
我爸爸是个自行车收藏家。
- [gasps]
（倒吸一口气）
- No further questions.
没有更多问题了。
- That thief even stole his vintage
那个小偷甚至偷了他的复古
Princess Peek-A-Boo bike.
公主躲猫猫自行车。
My dad is going to be so mad at me.
我爸会对我很生气的。
I could be grounded forever. What am I going to do?
我可能会被禁足一辈子。我该怎么办？
- Uh, maybe, the thief, or thieves, will realize
呃，也许，那个小偷，或者那些小偷，会意识到
they made a huge mistake, return the bike, and possibly
他们犯了一个巨大的错误，归还自行车，甚至可能
even apologize to the one who's been advising them
向一直劝阻他们犯罪生活的人道歉。
against their life of crime all along.
8: 或者那个自以为掌权的人
- Or maybe the one who thinks he's in charge
会意识到他大部分责任。
will realize he's mostly to blame.
呃，随便吧。如果你在附近看到任何可疑的人，
- Uh, whatever. If you see anybody suspicious
让我知道。如果再也见不到我...
in the neighborhood, let me know.
在附近看到任何可疑的人，告诉我。
And if you never see me again...
如果你们再也见不到我...
Dicky, I want you to have my hat.
迪基，我想把我的帽子留给你。
- Whoa.
哇。
I hope we never see you again.
我希望我们再也见不到你。
- Dooley, we're going to see you again.
杜利，我们会再见到你的。
You're just gonna get your dad's bikes back,
你只是要把你爸爸的自行车拿回来，
and everything is going to be okay.
一切都会好起来的。
- Thanks, it's nice to know that there are still
谢谢，知道世界上还有好人真好。
some good people in the world.
欢迎回家。
Welcome home.
[sighs]
[叹气]
- All right, we have to get those bikes
- 好吧，我们得把那些自行车
back to Dooley without him knowing.
偷偷还给杜利，不让他知道。
[all screaming]
[大家尖叫]
Somebody stole Dooley's bikes.
有人偷了杜利的自行车。
- Now that's the worst that could happen.
- 这真是最糟糕的情况了。
♪ ♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
- I can't believe someone stole the bikes we stole.
- 我简直不敢相信，有人偷了我们偷的自行车。
- What kind of world do we live in?
- 我们生活在一个什么样的世界？
- The garage door was closed.
- 车库门是关着的。
How'd they even get in?
他们是怎么进去的？
[glass clatters]
[玻璃碰撞声]
Oh, right.
哦，对了。
- Look, we have to get those bikes back.
- 听着，我们得把那些自行车找回来。
- What if we get a bike from Get Sporty and use that
- 如果我们从Get Sporty弄一辆自行车，用它做诱饵怎么样？
as bait for the thief? Then when he shows up
然后当小偷出现来偷这辆自行车时，我们可以跟踪他
to steal the bike, we can follow him back
回到他的藏身之处，把Dooley的自行车拿回来。
to his hideout and take Dooley's bikes back.
- 这说不通。
- That makes no sense.
- I've got an idea. What if we get a bike
- 我有个主意。如果我们从Get Sporty弄辆自行车
from Get Sporty and use it as bait for the thief?
用它来引诱小偷怎么样？
And then when he shows up to steal the bike,
然后等他出现来偷车时，
we follow him back to his lair and take Dooley's bikes back.
我们就跟踪他回到他的巢穴，把Dooley的自行车拿回来。
- Genius.
- 天才。
- That's exactly what I just said.
- 我刚刚说的就是这个。
- You never said "lair."
- 你没说“巢穴”。
all: Psh, "hideout."
大家都：切，“藏身处”。
♪
- I don't like this.
- 我不喜欢这个。
Look, I know this was originally my idea that Dawn stole--
听着，我知道这原本是我的主意，被Dawn偷走了——
- Improved.
- 改进了。
- Whatever. Are you sure we should be doing this?
- 无所谓。你确定我们应该这么做吗？
I mean, we're basically stealing a bike from Mom and Dad.
我的意思是，我们基本上是在从爸妈那里偷自行车。
- Look, Ricky, we're only borrowing the bike.
- 听着，Ricky，我们只是借用一下自行车。
We're gonna return it after we steal it back
我们会在从偷车贼那里偷回来之后还回去的。
from the bike thief who's gonna steal it from us.
那个偷车贼会从我们这里偷走的。
- Hideout plan sounds a lot less risky.
- 藏身之处计划听起来风险小多了。
all: Psh, "hideout."
大家都：嘁，“藏身之处”。
- Ricky's plans are the best, Ricky's plans are the best,
Ricky的计划是最好的，Ricky的计划是最好的，
Ricky's plans are the best.
Ricky的计划是最好的。
♪ ♪
- Okay, we've got the bait. Now all we have to do
好了，诱饵已经准备好了。现在我们只需要躲起来，等待小偷行动。
is hide and wait for the thief to do his thing.
哎呀，我把店门的钥匙放哪儿了？
- Uh-oh, what did I do with the keys to the store?
帮我找找。
Help me look.
别管钥匙了，自行车在哪儿？
- Forget the keys, where's the bike?
别管自行车了，窗户在哪儿？
- Forget the bike, where's the window?
哦，对了。Ricky把它打破了。
Oh, that's right. Ricky broke it.
♪ ♪
- I can't believe that bike thief stole that bike
我真不敢相信那个偷车贼偷走了那辆自行车，
without us even seeing him.
而我们甚至都没看到他。
- Yeah, well, we would've seen him if Ricky
是啊，如果Ricky没有分散我们的注意力，
hadn't distracted us wondering where he left
让我们找他放哪儿的店钥匙，
the keys to the store.
我们本可以看到他的。
- Maybe those keys will work.
也许那些钥匙能用。
- On the bright side, I mean, that's probably
从好的方面看，我是说，
the worst that could happen.
那可能是最糟糕的情况了。
Or this is.
或者这种情况也是。
- We've been robbed.
- 我们被抢劫了。
- They took everything.
- 他们拿走了所有东西。
- They took her head!
- 他们拿走了她的头！
- Well, at least we still have the keys.
- 好吧，至少我们还有钥匙。
- Well, that's a relief.
- 嗯，这算是个安慰。
- Oh, wait, where did I put them?
- 哦，等等，我把它们放哪儿了？
Oh, right, they're still in the door.
哦，对了，它们还在门上。
Hmm, well, wherever that door is,
嗯，不管那扇门在哪儿，
they're still in it.
它们还在那儿。
[clink]
[叮当]
- Who put this bull's-eye here?
谁把这靶子放在这儿的？
- Ahh, ahh, what's going on? - Let us out of here!
啊，啊，发生什么事了？ - 放我们出去！
- Are you guys okay? - Wait, who did this?
你们没事吧？ - 等等，这是谁干的？
- I did.
我干的。
all: Dooley?
杜利？
- You're the bike thief?
你是那个偷车贼？
- No, I am.
不，我是。
all: Grammy?
格莱米？
- Good behavior isn't its own reward,
良好的行为本身不是奖励，
a reward is its own reward.
奖励本身就是奖励。
Like one for catching criminals,
就像抓住罪犯的奖励，
which is why I am framing you.
这就是为什么我要陷害你。
Got 'em, officers.
抓到他们了，警官们。
[laughs] - Wait.
[笑] - 等等。
- There's your bike thieves. Now give me my reward.
- 这就是那些偷自行车的人。现在给我我的奖励。
- Here you go, ma'am. Two dozen new
- 给您，女士。两打新的
porcelain figurines for your bathroom.
浴室瓷器小雕像。
- Ooh, so worth it. Take 'em away.
- 哦，太值得了。带走他们。
Oh, not this one. He's innocent.
哦，不是这个。他是无辜的。
- But, Grammy, I was the one who did everything.
- 但是，奶奶，我才是做了所有事情的那个人。
- Oh, shh. You don't want to go to jail.
哦，嘘。你可不想进监狱。
You'd never be able to make a doody there.
在那里你肯定拉不出屎来。
- No, don't take us away! - It's all Ricky's fault!
不，别把我们带走！- 都是瑞奇的错！
- Please don't take us away!
求求你别把我们带走！
- Don't take us away!
别把我们带走！
- And you'd keep saying "don't take us away."
你还会不停地说“别把我们带走。”
Now that's the worst that could happen.
现在这就是最糟糕的情况了。
[splat] - Ahh!
啊！
[beeping]
（哔哔声）
- My chimichanga's ready.
我的玉米饼炸好了。
- Told you four minutes was too long.
- 告诉你四分钟太长了。
- That was a very entertaining little story, Ricky.
- 里奇，那真是个有趣的小故事。
- Yeah, but how's that the worst that could happen?
- 是啊，但这怎么算是最糟糕的呢？
In your fantasy, you got away with everything
在你的幻想中，你逃脱了一切
while we got taken away.
而我们却被带走了。
- You don't understand. It's the worst
- 你不明白。这是最糟糕的
that could've happened because you got taken away.
因为你们被带走了。
- Oh, please. - Really, that's why I'm always
- 哦，拜托。 - 真的，这就是为什么我总是
trying to get you to behave. The worst thing
试图让你守规矩。对我来说最糟糕的事
that could possibly happen to me is losing you guys.
就是失去你们。
I don't want anything to ever split us up.
我不希望任何事情把我们分开。
- Wow, Ricky, that's-- that's actually kind of nice.
- 哇，Ricky，那真是——那真是挺不错的。
- I'm touched, dude.
- 我感动了，伙计。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Don't worry,
- 别担心，
nothing's ever gonna split us up.
没有什么能把我们分开。
- [laughs] Look at them.
- [笑] 看他们。
- You know what, I was wrong. - [laughs]
- 你知道吗，我错了。 - [笑]
- Their good behavior isn't its own reward.
- 他们的良好行为不是他们自己的回报。
It's our reward.
这是我们的回报。
- Maybe we should let them open the present now.
也许我们现在应该让他们打开礼物。
- Ugh, looks like they've already started.
哎，看起来他们已经开始了。
- Hey, who took this out of the freezer?
嘿，谁把这从冰箱里拿出来了？
- We all did it. - Together.
我们大家都做了。
- And we'll all take the blame. - Together.
我们会一起承担责任。
- Who exploded a chimichanga in the microwave?
谁在微波炉里炸了墨西哥卷饼？
all: Uh, Mae did it!
呃，是梅做的！
- Oh, that's just chimi-wronga.
哦，那只是个错误的卷饼。
♪ ♪
- ♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
♪ 纳纳纳纳纳纳 纳纳纳纳纳纳 ♪
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
[whistling]
♪ [口哨声] ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶耶耶 耶耶 ♪
♪ 耶耶 耶耶耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶耶耶 耶耶 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶耶耶耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪